Gordon Kidd Teal papers, Inclusive: 1919-1990, undated, Bulk: 1950-1970, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Gordon Kidd Teal papers
Inclusive: 1919-1990, undated, Bulk: 1950-1970, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
3820
Teal, Dr. Gordon Kidd, 1907 - 2003
13 document boxes and 1 oversized box.
The Gordon Kidd Teal papers consist of school materials, personal materials, professional materials, and awards accumulated by Dr. Gordon Kidd Teal, a famous twentieth century scientist who graduated from Baylor University in 1927.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Gordon Kidd Teal was born in Dallas, Texas, on 1907 January 10, to Olin Allison and Azelia Clyde Kidd Teal. Gordon excelled in academics from an early age and graduated as valedictorian of Bryan Street High School in 1924.
For the next few years, Teal attended Baylor University where he continued to do well in academics and sports. Teal served as the President of the Scholarship Society and Latin Club, the Vice President of the Senior Class, a member of the Baylor Chamber of Commerce, and a member of the track team. He graduated from Baylor University in 1927 with a Bachelor of Arts in Mathematics and Chemistry.
Teal continued his education at Brown University where he earned his Master’s degree (1928) and his Ph.D. in Chemistry (1931). Under the tutelage of Dr. Charles Kraus, Teal examined the chemical and electric properties of germanium, which to that point had been deemed relatively useless by most scientists. On 1931 March 7, Teal married Lyda Louise Smith with whom he had three sons: Robert Carroll, Donald Fraser, and Stephen O’Banion Teal.
As early as 1930, Teal had begun his productive scientific career at Bell Telephone Laboratories. For the next twenty-two years, Teal made one scientific discovery after another. He perfected the growth of high purity single crystal germanium and silicon, co-developed the junction transistor, created the grown junction single crystal technique, and secured approximately forty-five patents. In 1952, Teal moved back to Texas when a position opened at Texas Instruments.
In 1953, Gordon Teal was hired as an Assistant Vice President at Texas Instruments. Arguably his greatest invention, the first commercial silicon transistor (1954), launched Texas Instruments into a period of unprecedented success. The military, astronomical, and commercial implications for such a transistor were limitless and resulted in many of the innovative technologies our society enjoys today. Teal worked at Texas Instruments until 1965 when he was appointed the first Director of the Institute for Materials Research at the National Bureau of Standards. He served a two-year term, and then returned to Texas Instruments where he remained until retirement in 1972.
Retirement, however, did not mean idleness for Gordon Teal. Along with his numerous awards and honorary degrees, Teal continued to serve as a consultant for both Texas Instruments and the Department of Defense. Throughout his life, Teal was actively involved in many scientific organizations including the American Association for the Advancement of Science, American Chemical Society, American Institute of Chemists, American Institute of Electrical Engineers, American Physical Society, Council of Scientific and Engineering Societies of Dallas-Fort Worth, Institute of Electrical and Electronic Engineers, Institute of Radio Engineers, and the Texas Academy of Science. Dr. Gordon Teal passed away on 2003 January 7.
Scope and Content
The Gordon Kidd Teal papers span from 1919 until 1990. Series I. School Work consists of various notebooks and reports created by Teal during his studies at Baylor University and Brown University. Series II. Personal contains biographical materials collected by Teal and others. Series III. Professional Work, by far the largest series in the collection, consists of materials from Teal's positions at Bell Telephone Laboratories and Texas Instruments as well as his research interests and involvements in scientific organizations. The final series consists of awards and certificates awarded to Teal throughout his life.
Arrangement
The Gordon Kidd Teal papers were initially housed in five large banker boxes. There was prior organization, which has been recorded in a folder inventory. However, this organization was unhelpful in some areas, because there were a number of folders with no titles and over two boxes of duplicates.
After being processed, the Gordon Kidd Teal papers are organized into four series: I. School Work, II. Personal, III. Professional Work, and IV. Awards. In each series, the materials are classified by type.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 3820. Acquired 2002-02-07
Related Resources
Related references
"Baylor's Gift to Twentieth Century Scientific Technology." Baylor Line Vol. XXVI, No. 5 (1964 September-October): 8-13.
Gordon Kidd Teal Papers, Accession #3820, Box #4, Folders #1-4, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
National Inventors Hall of Fame. "Meet the 2009 National Inventors Hall of Fame Inductees." Accessed 2012 November 6.
PBS. "Gordon Teal." Accessed 2012 November 6.
Index Terms
Subjects (Persons)
Teal, Gordon Kidd, 1907-2003.
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Alumni and alumnae.; Bell Telephone Laboratories, Inc.; Institute of Radio Engineers.; Texas Academy of Science; Texas Instruments Incorporated
Subjects
Germanium.; Scientists -- United States.; Silicon.; Transistors.
Genres
Awards.; Brochures.; Correspondence.; Essays.; Minutes (Records); Periodicals.; Programs.; Research notes.; Speeches.
- School Work, 1926-1963; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains notebooks, notes, essays, and reports from Gordon Teal's school work at Baylor University, Brown University, as well as post-doctoral work. The materials are in average to good condition.
  - School Work: Essay: Gordon Kidd Teal and Charles Kraus: “Compounds of Germanium and Hydrogen”, 1931 May (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - School Work: Essays: General (1 of 3), 1932-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - School Work: Essays: General (2 of 3), 1932-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - School Work: Essays: General (3 of 3), 1932-1963, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (1 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (2 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (3 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (4 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (5 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (6 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - School Work: Negative Photostats: Research Notes (7 of 7), undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - School Work: Notebook: Chemistry: Ledger, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - School Work: Notebook: Chemistry: Loose Materials, 1928-1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - School Work: Notebook: Gordon Kidd Teal: Baylor University: Chemistry 220, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - School Work: Notebook: Gordon Kidd Teal: Baylor University: Math 262, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - School Work: Notebook: Gordon Kidd Teal: Theoretical Chemistry I, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - School Work: Notebook: Gordon Kidd Teal: Theoretical Chemistry II, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (1 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (2 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (3 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (4 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (5 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics” (6 of 6), undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics”: Loose Materials (1 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics”: Loose Materials (2 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - School Work: Notebook: “Notes on Statistical Mechanics”: Loose Materials (3 of 3), undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (1 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (2 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (3 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (4 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (5 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (6 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (7 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (8 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (9 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (10 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (11 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (12 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Handwritten (13 of 13), undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Typed (1 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - School Work: Notes: Chemistry: Typed (2 of 2), undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - School Work: Notes: Introduction to Quantum Mechanics, undated (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - School Work: Report: “Theoretical Chemistry” (1 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - School Work: Report: “Theoretical Chemistry” (2 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - School Work: Report: “Theoretical Chemistry” (3 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - School Work: Report: “Theoretical Chemistry” (4 of 4), undated (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Personal, 1919-1990; 2
  This small series contains personal materials pertaining to Gordon Teal, particularly biographical materials, outlines of his professional activities, and a Who's Who article. A 53-page biographical summary of Teal's life is of particular importance for anyone hoping to write a biography of Teal. The materials are in average to good condition.
  - Personal: Appendices: “Biographical Summary of Gordon K. Teal”, undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Personal: Application: Who’s Who in America: Gordon Kidd Teal, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Personal: Biographical Materials: Gordon Kidd Teal, undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Personal: Outline: “Biographical Summary of Gordon K. Teal”, 1972 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Personal: Periodical: Baptists: The Watchman-Examiner, 1919 May 8 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Personal: Summary: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Washington Activities and Accomplishments”, 1967 August 7 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Professional Work, 1919-1984; 3
  This series, the largest of the collection, contains a vast array of materials pertaining to Gordon Teal's professional life. Literary productions and correspondence from Teal's positions at Bell Telephone Laboratories, Texas Instruments, and the National Bureau of Standards are prevalent, but the series also contains correspondence and minutes from his involvement in scientific organizations including the Texas Academy of Science, the Institute of Radio Engineers, and the American Institute of Chemists. A number of Teal's notebooks are also included. The materials are in good condition.
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: 34th Fellows Lecture: “Chemistry: The Ubiquitous Science”, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Integrating Diversified Technology into Profitable Programs”, 1960 January 21 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Introduction of Pat Haggerty”, 1969 March 18 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Meeting the Scientific and Technological Needs of Our National Economy”, 1957 September 11 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Patterns of Creative Action in a Research Career”, 1967 June 15-17 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Reflections Upon Receiving the Medal of Honor”, 1968 March 20 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: SDP Technical Seminar: “Current Research Activity Throughout TI” (1 of 2), 1962 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: SDP Technical Seminar: “Current Research Activity Throughout TI” (2 of 2), 1962 August 14 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Solid State Devices, Materials, and Processes - - Past and Future”, 1958 June 24 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Summary of the Current State of Research Management”, 1968 December 30 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: Summer Institute: Texas A&M: Rough Draft, 1961 June 21 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: Summer Institute: Texas A&M: “Semiconductor Physics, Materials Technology and Devices”, 1961 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Technical Highlights of Texas Instruments, 1952-1962.”, 1962 November 12 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Technology and Human Potential”, 1970 December 28 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Texas Instruments and Space-Summary”, 1962 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “The 25th Anniversary of the Silicon Transistor”, 1980 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: “The NBS Matter and Materials Data and Standards Program”, 1966 October 11 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: Third Technical Seminar (1 of 2), 1959 October (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Professional Work: Address: Gordon Kidd Teal: Third Technical Seminar (2 of 2), 1959 October (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Professional Work: Address: Mervin J. Kelly: “The Work and Environment of the Physicist”, 1957 May (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Professional Work: Address: Patrick Haggerty: “Inflation and the American Standard of Living” (1 of 2), 1970 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Professional Work: Address: Patrick Haggerty: “Inflation and the American Standard of Living” (2 of 2), 1970 May 9 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Professional Work: Address: Texas Academy of Science: President Donald Duncan, 1962 November 30 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Professional Work: Addresses: Gordon Kidd Teal: General, 1956 October 16- 1962 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Professional Work: Agenda: Taiwan Trip, 1975 August (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Professional Work: Agreement: Institute of Radio Engineers: San Francisco and Los Angeles Sections, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Professional Work: Announcements: National Pilot Study of Science and Mathematics, 1961 March 2-10 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (1 of 4), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (2 of 4), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (3 of 4), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (4 of 4), 1958 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (1 of 3), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (2 of 3), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (3 of 3), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (1 of 2), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (2 of 2), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (1 of 4), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (2 of 4), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (3 of 4), 1961 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (4 of 4), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (1 of 2), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Professional Work: Applications: Institute of Radio Engineers: Fellow Awards (2 of 2), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal and George MacWood: “The Raman Spectra of the Isotopic Molecules H2, HD, and D2”, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal and Harold C. Urey: Reviews of Modern Physics: “The Hydrogen Isotope of Atomic Weight Two”, 1935 January (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal, J.R. Fisher, and A.W. Treptow: “A New Bridge Photo-Cell Employing a Photo-Conductive Effect in Silicon”, 1946 November (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal, M. Sparks, and E. Buehler: “Single-Crystal Germanium”, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Roots of Creative Research”, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Professional Work: Article: Gordon Kidd Teal: “Single Crystals of Germanium and Silicon- Basic to the Transistor and Integrated Circuit”, 1976 July (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Professional Work: Article: P.P. Debye and E.M. Conwell: Physical Review: “Electrical Properties of N-Type Germanium”, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Professional Work: Article: Revolution in Miniature: “A New Industry”, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Professional Work: Article: Richard Petritz: “Contributions of Materials Technology to Semiconductor Devices”, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Professional Work: Article: Texins: “The Transistor and TI”, 1953 August (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Professional Work: Article: The Baylor Line: “Baylor’s Gift to Twentieth Century Scientific Technology”, 1964 September-October (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Professional Work: Booklet: “Information Booklet on Physics Organizations Abroad”, 1962 May (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Professional Work: Booklet: U.S. Department of Commerce: “Measurement-Pacemaker of American Growth”, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Professional Work: Brochure: “Finding a World of Oil, Facts About GSI and Its Relation to You”, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Professional Work: Brochure: Sampo Corporation, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Professional Work: Brochure: Sony Entertainment, undated (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Professional Work: Brochure: “Travel Insurance Information for Academy Personnel”, undated (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Professional Work: By-Laws: Institute of Radio Engineers: Board of Directors (1 of 2), 1959 April 8 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Professional Work: By-Laws: Institute of Radio Engineers: Board of Directors (2 of 2), 1959 April 8 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Professional Work: Citations: Texas Academy of Science (1 of 2), 1961 December 8 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Professional Work: Citations: Texas Academy of Science (2 of 2), 1961 December 8 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Professional Work: Clippings: General, 1948 January 29- 1962 December (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Professional Work: Clippings: General, 1963 February- 1967 April (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Professional Work: Clippings: General, 1967 May- 1970 September (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Professional Work: Clippings: General, 1971-1974, undated (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Professional Work: Clippings: Texas Academy of Science, 1960, undated (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1952 January 1-1953 October 21 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1953 October 30- November 16 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1953 November 19- December 2 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1953 December 5-27 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1953 December 28- 1954 January 19 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1954 January 22- February 10 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1954 August 5- 1955 May 6 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1955 September 23- 1956 January 12 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 January 12- February 28 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 March 1-20 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 March 21-29 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 April 2-6 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 April 16- August 17 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1956 August 23- 1957 March 12 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: American Chemical Society, 1957 April 2- September 4 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Institute of Radio Engineers: Awards Committee, 1958 May 13- 1960 February 3 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Institute of Radio Engineers: Awards Committee, 1961 March 10- August 16 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: General, 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: General, 1956-1988 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Taiwan Trip, 1975 June 10- November 19 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1953 October 12- 1958 March 20 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1958 October 23- 1959 November 10 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1959 December 1- 1960 May 23 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1960 May 23- July 21 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1960 July 21- August 3 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1960 August 8- December 12 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Professional Work: Correspondence: Texas Academy of Science, 1961 January 30- April 19 (Box 5, Folder 14)